# Maxim Kashchenko

Thailand +66 83-079-2969 mkaschenko@me.com https://mkaschenko.github.io https://github.com/mkaschenko

His path began in a technical university where he was studying "Informatics and Computer Science" (bachelor) and "Databases" (master). Less than a year after the beginning he got his first job in a local software development company. Combining work with study he graduated from the university and got working experience in a couple outsourcing companies and one product as well.

Being freelancer for a while and travelling around Southeast Asia he settled down in Bangkok. Continuing his path Maxim worked for some companies, led some teams, used some programming languages.

Overall during a decade career he was solving problems in different domains such as: crawling and parsing, CMS (Content Management Systems), e-commerce, scheduling systems, review sites, affiliate programs, virtual data rooms, real estate, visual analytic platforms for retail banks, personal insurance in USA, education platforms and others.

His main language is Ruby, also he is familiar with Clojure (the favourite one) and gained some knowledge in SQL, TypeScript.

### **Technical Skills**

Likes: ruby clojure sql typescript

Dislikes: angular

## **Experience**

### Software engineer / Team lead - Lockstep Labs

Feb 2016 → Feb 2019

ruby, clojure, typescript, postgresql, ruby-on-rails, reactjs, redux, bem, redis, circleci, git

Domains: e-commerce, visual analytic platforms for retail banks, personal insurance in USA, education platforms.

Languages: Ruby, Clojure, SQL, JavaScript/TypeScript.

Participated in development of web applications using different programming languages. Worked within various teams in the company, led some of them on some projects.

## $\textbf{Software engineer} - \underline{\mathsf{HipFlat}}$

Aug 2014 → Oct 2015

ruby, javascript, mongodb, sidekiq, ruby-on-rails, redis, algolia, codeship, git

Domains: crawling and parsing, real estate

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript.

Participated in development of the product mostly using Ruby on Rails as an API service. Dedicated his time to architecture and performance of the backend system. Was responsible for the crawling and parsing systems.

Ruby on Rails Developer / Team Lead – Arhont Information Security ruby, postgresql, tdd, ruby-on-rails, redis, mongodb, ocr, circleci, git

 $\textit{Mar}\ 2012 \rightarrow \textit{Aug}\ 2014$ 

Domains: virtual data rooms, parsing.

Languages: Ruby, SQL.

Participated in development of the product mostly using Ruby on Rails as an API service. Dedicated his time to architecture and performance of the backend system. Led the team for some period of time and applied some agile technics.

 $\textbf{Ruby on Rails Developer} - \underline{\text{Tulp.ru}}$ 

ruby, javascript, postgresql, ruby-on-rails, sphinx, redis, git, jquery

 $\textit{Mar 2010} \rightarrow \textit{Oct 2011}$ 

Domains: review sites.

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript.

Participated in development of the product mostly using Ruby on Rails. Some agile technics were applied as well.

Ruby on Rails Developer - JazzCloud

ruby, javascript, ruby-on-rails, postgresql, amazon-web-services, jquery, html, git

Domains: e-commerce, scheduling systems.

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript.

Participated in development of web applications mostly using Ruby on Rails.

Ruby on Rails Developer - Development mill

ruby, ruby-on-rails, svn, git, html, jquery

Languages: Ruby.

Participated in development of web applications mostly using Ruby on Rails.

Domains: crawling and parsing, CMS (Content Management Systems).

**Education** 

Unfinished Master's degree, Databases – Omsk State Technical University (OSTU)

database, networking, software-design, software-development, math

Main subjects: databases, networks, software design and development, mathematics.

**B.S. Informatics and Computer Science** – Omsk State Technical University (OSTU) math, physics, informatica, software-design, software-development, database

Main subjects: mathematics, physics, informatics, software design and development, databases.

Readings

**Test Driven Development (The Addison-Wesley Signature Series)** – Kent Beck – http://www.amazon.co.uk/Driven-Development-Addison-Wesley-Signature-Series/dp/0321146530

On the criteria to be used in decomposing systems into modules – D. L Parnas – http://www.amazon.co.uk/criteria-used-decomposing-systems-modules/dp/B0007BQZVU

Refactoring: Improving the Design of Existing Code (Addison-Wesley Object Technology Series) – Martin Fowler, Kent Beck, John Brant, William Opdyke, Don Roberts – http://www.amazon.co.uk/Refactoring-Improving-Existing-Addison-Wesley-Technology-ebook/dp/B007WTFWJ6

**Quantum Psychology: How Brain Software Programs You and Your World** – Robert Anton Wilson – http://www.amazon.co.uk/Quantum-Psychology-Brain-Software-Programs/dp/1561840718

Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs (MIT Electrical Engineering and Computer Science) – Harold Abelson, Gerald Jay Sussman, Julie Sussman – https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43713.Structure\_and\_Interpretation\_of\_Computer\_Programs

Tools

Favorite Editor: Emacs

Sep 2009 → Mar 2010

Jun 2007 → Aug 2009

2010 → 2011

 $2006 \rightarrow 2010$